WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
I'll have to go.
Of course you must go.
Oh, but who'll give the letter
to her ladyship?
Oh, I can do that and I'll take
her breakfast and dress her today,
but I haven't got time
to make it a regular thing.
No, I can do it until she finds
someone else. Lady Mary won't mind.
What's the matter with you?
Miss O'Brien's upped and left!
Never!
Jimmy!
Jimmy. Miss O'Brien's gone!
What? Gone where?
How should I know?
Madge, O'Brien's gone.
- Have you heard?
- Heard what?
- Miss O'Brien? She's gone.
- What do you mean gone?
She's left.
Left?
She's packed up.
I can't believe it.
I can. Sneaking off like a thief
in the night, that's O'Brien to a T.
I just can't believe
Susan has done this to me.
Miss O'Brien did say that she got on
very well with Lady Flintshire
when she was up in Scotland.
So I gather!
"Lady Flintshire has booked
my ticket for India
"and it seems too good
a chance to miss."
Was there really no warning?
Now I think of it,
she'd a telegram yesterday.
That must have been it.
So what happens now?
I'll dress you today, m'lady,
and Anna will take over tomorrow,
until you find a replacement.
And she really gave no clue?
She didn't say anything to me,
Mr Carson, not a word.
As long as she didn't.
I know you all think she must have
said summat, but she didn't.
I believe you. Thousands wouldn't.
She may be my aunt
but she's a dark horse.
No-one will contradict you there.
Susan Flintshire
has stolen Mama's maid
whilst her daughter's
a guest in this house?
I'm sure she wouldn't
put it like that.
I don't care how she puts it.
It's absolutely disgraceful.
It's all right. Madge told me.
It is NOT all right.
Did you have any idea?
No. Not really.
I knew, I knew that Mummy thought
O'Brien was very good at doing hair,
and they talked about her
wanting to travel...
What? When?
When you were all at Duneagle.
And you didn't think to inform us?
I'm in London tomorrow. I can put
an advertisement in The Lady.
Good.
Won't it take forever, waiting for
the magazine to come out?
It can't be helped.
We're meeting Trent at eleven.
I'll see you there. I want to walk
the plantations first.
I was wondering if Mary
might like to come.
Don't bother Mary.
She's got enough on her plate.
Did you really not know anything?
I never thought
she'd go through with it.
I thought you might like
to take this down with you.
In case you want a walk.
It's quite chilly.
Where's the black one?
I'm taking Master George out
for some air, m'lady,
and I wondered if you'd
like to come with us.
I don't think so, but thank you.
Poor little orphan.
Thank you, Nanny.
He's not an orphan.
He's got his mother.
Orphans haven't.
He isn't poor either, come to that.
And you don't mind
my seeing to her ladyship?
Why would I mind? I'm not planning
a trip round the world.
Mr Molesley. Have you seen Mr Travis?
I need to speak to him about
the Bring and Buy Sale.
I'm afraid not, your ladyship.
Never mind.
This were a sad business.
Very, very sad.
I can't believe it's time
for the stone already.
Six months.
They always leave six months
for the grave to settle.
Tell me has, has your son
found another job, yet?
No, m'lady.
They've let him stay on and he
always tries to make himself useful,
but it can't go on forever
and anyway, he's lost his wage.
But he's a properly trained valet!
He could even be a butler.
I hope so, m'lady...
..but it's a changing world.
You don't have to tell me.
Hello.
It'll soon be time for you
to get out and walk, young lady.
Please don't touch the children,
not without my permission.
What?
They are in my charge
and I cannot be too careful.
I would remind you that I knew
this young girl's mother,
which you never did.
That doesn't make you her friend.
As a matter of fact, it does.
Well, I can't stay here
to bandy words.
Will you ask Mrs Patmore
to send up the children's luncheon
in half an hour?
Ask her yourself, why don't you?
Was her ladyship very disappointed?
She was, and it'll take quite
a while to find a replacement.
I can't believe Miss O'Brien
would be so thoughtless.
Can't you? I can.
She wants an adventure.
What's wrong with that?
I don't blame her.
Not for wanting to go, but why
run off and leave us in the lurch?
You're talking like that
so we'll think you didn't know.
That's not kind!
What's the good of a month
of sour looks? Good luck to her.
How was Lady Mary this morning?
The same.
But, I suppose she must
come out of it eventually.
For Master George's sake,
if for no other reason.
I hope so. Right now, she prefers
to leave it all to Nanny West.
I couldn't be a nanny.
Why not? Don't you like children?
No, I do.
Being a nanny you're not one of
the family but not one of us either.
What are you talking about?
Being a nanny.
Daisy was saying she thinks
it must be a lonely life.
I don't know about that.
But if you ask me, that Nanny West
thinks too much of herself.
Why? What's she done?
She always seems nice to me.
She only tried to give me orders.
You mean she mistook you
for a servant?
But he IS a servant. Don't tell him.
He'll never get over the shock!
Thank you, Mr Marsh.
He was bound
to be disappointed.
You're sure you want to
abandon the whole plan?
We don't have a choice.
We have to find the death duties
on half the estate.
They'll be merciless.
I know.
But, I wish we could wait for Mary
to come back into play.
She isn't a player.
She has a life interest in one third
of Matthew's share of Downton,
and a third of his
other possessions,
but everything else
belongs to little George.
And that's all the law gives her?
He should have made a will.
But, Mary's George's guardian.
Surely that gives her
some sort of say?
It's a moot point.
Since I own the other
half of everything,
isn't it more appropriate for me
to manage the boy's fortunes?
Besides, she's in such
a fragile state,
the last thing I want is for her
to start worrying about money.
Of course. But you don't think...?
You've seen her!
She hardly has the energy
to lift a fork to her mouth.
She loved him very much.
And the price of great love is
great misery when one of you dies.
I know that.
Of course you do.
I'm so sorry.
We better get back
or we'll be late for lunch.
I've placed advertisements,
Mr Carson, you know I have.
But the answers weren't suitable?
I didn't get any answers.
Well, I did, but when I wrote back,
I heard nothing more.
Well, I don't know what to suggest.
Because, I can't stay here?
Mr Molesley, I should hate us
to appear inhospitable.
But I can't stay here.
Is it fair on his lordship?
It has been six months.
I suppose I could go to my dad's
until I get something sorted.
What a good idea.
Servants' lunch is on the table.
Thank you, Mrs Patmore.
Oh cheer up, Mr Molesley.
It may never happen.
It already has.
I'm going into Thirsk after lunch.
Do you want to come?
I'm walking down to the village
to see how Isobel's getting on.
Remind her it's an open invitation,
if she wants to see her grandson
or feels like company,
she just has to turn up.
I'll tell her.
I might come with you.
I don't think so.
I don't think she's up
to seeing many people.
I only meant into the village.
Edith, are you really going
to London tomorrow?
I have a couple of errands
if you are.
I'm seeing Michael Gregson.
He must have missed you.
He's giving a party to introduce me
to his literary friends.
How exciting. Isn't it, Robert?
I... I was wondering if I might
put a card in your window.
A card, m'lady?
For a job asking for applicants.
And what sort of job might this be?
Why? Does it make a difference?
No, I suppose not.
Thank you.
Erm, how much will that be?
Sixpence should cover it.
You ought to see more of George.
Poor George.
What a burden he is born into.
A baby rich as Croesus
and a mother almost passed over.
That's the law.
It seems so strange.
Matthew was always so meticulous.
He thought that death
was many years away.
And so it should have been.
If there's anything I can do to help,
please let me do it.
I'm grateful.
But you see,
when your only child dies...
..then you're not a mother any more.
You're not anything, really.
That's what I'm trying
to get used to.
You're a grandmother.
And I know you're going to be
a wonderful one.
Afternoon post.
Ah, thank you.
Oh, not this again.
Not what?
Oh... nothing!
Let me know when
the upholsterer arrives.
I want to be there when you
explain the job in hand.
Very well, but I can easily manage.
He needs to grasp the quality
of the tapestry on the chairs,
before he starts
slamming nails into them.
And I couldn't make him see that?
Just closing, love.
I only wanted to know who was
looking for a lady's maid.
There's not too many in Downton
who need a lady's maid.
You mean the Abbey?
Didn't you used to work there?
I did, but I've been
studying since then.
Studying for what?
To become a lady's maid.
Madge says that Lady Edith
saw Mrs Crawley this afternoon.
How is she?
In a very dark place, I'm afraid.
And no wonder.
For a widowed mother
to lose an only son...
There's no more fit person
to comfort her than you.
I wonder.
If Lady Sybil had been an only child
I believe I'd have died.
No, m'lady.
You would have lived on for the baby.
And so must she.
Thank you so much, Mrs Hughes,
and good night to you.
Good night, m'lady.
M'lord.
Are you all right?
I feel we must settle the question of
who is to manage the baby's property.
I don't want to hurry Mary
before she's ready.
What question? She's George's
mother and his guardian.
Of course she is, but when it comes
to decisions about the estate,
shouldn't it be me?
Why?
Because, together, my grandson and I
own five sixths of Downton.
Mary's share is only for her life.
She couldn't do much with it
even if she wanted to.
The point being that with
the death duties we're facing,
there are some big decisions ahead.
You want to push Mary out.
I'm not pushing her out.
She was never "in."
Matthew was co-owner
and now his son is.
I worked with Matthew.
I must work for his boy.
Thanks.
A lot of letters for a Tuesday.
How do people have time to write
when the week is just beginning?
It's Saint Valentine's Day.
Oh, imagine your remembering that
and my forgetting it.
Who would have thought such a thing?
I am not a complete stranger
to romance
if that's what you're implying.
Maybe I am now, but I wasn't always.
Hold on.
I thought these were all bills.
Daisy! This one's for you.
Daisy? Who's that from?
Don't tease her, Mr Barrow.
Who sent you a card?
I don't know. It's not signed.
Nor's mine.
We both must have secret admirers.
Which is no more than we deserve.
That's enough of that, Mr Bates.
We've work to do.
What's that?
Nothing.
Of course. It's Valentine's Day.
When are you leaving for London?
I'm catching the ten o'clock.
I ought to pack.
Have a happy time.
Just down there.
Mr Grigg?
Do I know you?
You wrote to Charlie Carson
at Downton Abbey.
I work with him.
Did he send you?
Not exactly. In a way.
What... What did he say about me?
What does he plan to do?
Mr Carson is very busy.
He wanted me to find out how you are.
Then, I think
he'll come up with a plan.
I knew it.
He said some harsh things
when we last met,
but, we go back a long way,
Charlie and me.
And whatever's happened,
to theatre folk like us,
that means something.
Yes, I'm sure it does.
Thank you, Madam.
Thank you.
This is very lovely.
Shouldn't you be at the office?
Aunt Rosamund's sending her car.
I've missed you. I haven't stopped
thinking about you for one moment.
Well, I'm here now.
I couldn't be more thrilled
because I've got some news...
Well, not news, more an idea.
Go on.
I've done some research,
and discovered not every country
is the same as England.
You amaze me!
No, I mean there are places where
lunacy is grounds for divorce,
Portugal and Greece
and even Germany.
But, wouldn't you have to live there?
No, no, I'm just finding out
what's involved.
But if I did live in Germany,
would you come with me?
Oh. Hello, Burns.
This is Burns,
Aunt Rosamund's chauffeur.
Good afternoon, m'lady.
Can I give you a lift?
I'll take a taxi.
It's the opposite direction.
I'll see you tonight.
Oh. Am I too early?
No. I'm afraid tea
was a little late.
Oh, dear. Can you manage?
Should I give you a hand?
I can manage, thank you, Miss West.
Come to me, darling.
Hello.
Now, here's the little Prince,
m'lady.
See how happy he is to see his
beautiful Mama?
God bless him.
Thank you, Nanny.
You say you have no purpose,
but what about little George?
Surely you're interested in him?
Of course, but I'm not going to
drive Mary mad by interfering.
It's the job of grandmothers
to interfere.
Oh, that's Molesley.
He asked to see me and I told him
when he could come.
Oh? Well, may I stay?
Or is it a secret assignation?
Oh. I'm very sorry to interrupt
your ladyship.
What is it, Molesley?
I came to ask if you'd consider
giving me my old job back.
I apologise for forcing myself
on a private conversation.
I will go.
No please, m'lady.
There's no mystery.
I've lost my job, because,
well, for obvious reasons
and I thought I'd ask here.
The trouble is,
I have no need for a butler.
These days I'm just an old widow
who eats off a tray.
I see.
Just because you're an old widow,
I see no necessity to eat off a tray.
You and I are different.
Yes, that is very true.
I'm wasting your time.
Should, should we hear
of an opening...
..where would we find you?
I'm moving to my father's house
today, m'lady.
Have you had any more time
to think about what I said?
You mean our living in sin?
We'd only live in sin as you call it,
until the divorce.
Don't you want to be with me?
You know I do. More than anything.
Erm, is there any more gin, sir?
We're running rather low.
Yes, I'll er, I'll have a look.
Oh, my Lord!
This is an honour, your ladyship.
I have a message for your son.
Lady Shackleton is
joining me for luncheon.
I want him to come and help.
But, what about Mr Spratt?
Well, Spratt will be there,
of course,
but Molesley can still
take an active part.
Lady Shackleton tells me
her butler is retiring.
Won't she have made arrangements
to find another?
But that is the point.
She hasn't yet decided
whether to replace him or not,
so if Molesley can
demonstrate his skills...
Mr Spratt won't mind?
It is not his business to mind.
No. Well...
Very good, m'lady.
Thank you very much.
You took a letter out
of my waste paper basket
when I had clearly crumpled it
and thrown it away?
I could see it had upset you.
I wanted to know why.
I'm sure.
But it didn't occur to you it might
not be your concern WHY I was upset?
Well, anyway, I did it and I read it
and I went to see him!
Don't you want to know how he is?
If I wanted to know how he is,
I would have answered his letter.
Mr Carson, he's in the workhouse!
And in case you're wondering,
it's as bad as if we were reading
about it in a novel by Dickens.
Haven't they closed the workhouses?
No. They haven't. Not all of them.
Well, at least he's in the dry.
If you can call it dry when there's
mould in the very air you breathe.
This is a man
you sang and danced with.
Do you feel nothing?
I don't feel I could be helpful, no.
And I would thank you
not to remind me
of a time in my life
I prefer to forget.
But why would we need it?
It's a mixer. It beats eggs
and whips cream and all sorts.
But you and Ivy do that!
And we'd be glad not to,
thank you very much.
Did Lady Edith say why she got it?
Her ladyship asked her to.
She wants to save us a bit of
elbow grease. You don't understand!
Before too long,
her ladyship could run the kitchen
with a woman from the village.
What with these toasters and mixers
and such like, we'd be out of a job.
I want to try it.
Then on your own head be it!
Did you like your card, Ivy?
What's it to you?
That'd be telling.
Don't listen. He's just teasing.
Come on. Clear out, you two.
There's work to be done.
Do you think that means
that Jimmy sent it?
Maybe he thinks it fun to tease.
But, don't you see?
If Jimmy sent mine,
then who sent yours?
Thomas?
Mr Barrow to you.
Can you tell Mrs Patmore
I won't want the scrambled egg
for Miss Sybbie's tea.
If you go through here and down the
stairs, you can tell her yourself.
Do it. Please. I can't stop.
The children are on their own.
Why did I struggle across London
if Rose was going to sort it out?
You had other things to do.
It doesn't explain why Rose put
the card in the Post Office window.
I just thought how much quicker
it would be if we could
find someone local.
I do feel responsible.
Have you had any answers yet?
We've had three and one's promising,
so we'll see her in Ripon on Friday.
Why isn't she coming here?
She's looking after her aunt,
she can't get away.
It's time for you
to come back to us.
What would you suggest?
Take an interest in something,
doesn't matter what.
Poetry... or carpentry.
History or hats.
I'm interested in George.
Are you?
I will be.
What have you been doing today?
Well, it's this whole business
with the repair shop.
Tom, don't bore her
with all that nonsense.
It's my fault. I asked.
Even so.
You concentrate on feeling better.
You mustn't worry about
anything else.
Did you send a Valentine's card?
Suppose I did.
Was it to Ivy?
That's my business.
You didn't really
send Ivy a card?
Is it likely?
I sent one to Lady Anstruther.
I worked for her and
she's coming back from France.
She might be useful.
Wasn't that a bit forward?
Oh, I don't think she'll mind.
To be honest, Mrs Hughes,
I don't see that
it's any of my business.
That's something I never thought
I'd hear you say, ma'am.
A wretched man is in the workhouse
and he reaches out to us for rescue.
Well, he reached out to Carson.
I don't see what you want me to do.
Mrs Crawley, I...
I wondered
if I could bring him here.
Here?
If you and I were to vouch for him
to the authorities,
I'm sure we could get him
away from that place.
But why here? Why not the Abbey?
Isn't he Carson's responsibility?
I'm sorry to say it, but, Mr Carson
has turned his back on his old pal.
I see.
So you want to risk Carson's wrath
by rescuing this Mr Grigg?
He's a pitiful being,
but he's not beyond work.
He's not beyond a decent life,
if he could find it.
You see, in my present state,
I don't think I'm strong enough...
But you are, ma'am!
If you could just
set aside your grief,
and use that strength
for another's good.
Mr Branson.
Mr Carson.
I know you won't think it correct,
but I need to ask your help
in a difficult situation.
My help, sir?
Lord Grantham is against me in this.
With Matthew gone,
I've no-one else to turn to.
Mary, that is, Lady Mary,
is not improving.
She's suffered a terrible tragedy.
Of course.
But it's six months now,
and she's no better than she was
a week after he died.
The only way is for her to find
an interest outside of herself,
and I know that should be
in the running of the estate.
What does his lordship think?
Lord Grantham thinks his duty
is to protect Mary and her son
by managing everything himself.
And he won't listen to you
on the subject?
He sees her as a little woman,
who shouldn't be troubled by
anything so harsh as reality.
And even were I to agree with you...
..how could I help?
Give her advice.
She'd take it from you.
What makes you say that?
Because she knows you only
want the best for her.
I'm going down to the pub tonight.
When?
After our supper. I'm bored.
I want to stretch my legs.
You can't. It's not your day off.
I can go for a walk, can't I?
- I could never do that.
- Don't be so soft.
I couldn't. I'd keep thinking
I were going to be electrocuted.
You should have more faith.
More courage!
How about some Dutch courage, Ivy?
Why not come with me, tonight?
What? Me go to a pub?
Without leave? You must be mad.
Don't you ever want to
take a chance in life?
When would we be back?
You're not thinking of going?!
I don't know.
I never do anything
I'm not supposed to.
What are you not supposed to do?
Nothing.
What's going on there?
I'm making the mousse for tonight.
Oh, my God. Well, we'd better have
some soup put by.
I'd rather not rely on
that contraption.
Can I help you?
I doubt you would if you could.
I'm sorry?
Why didn't you give my instructions
to Mrs Patmore about the eggs?
Because I didn't feel like it.
Besides, why can't Miss Sybbie
have an egg to her tea?
I don't have to explain
my decisions to you.
You're a member of staff,
and the orders I give
are to be obeyed.
And aren't you a member of staff?
Not in that way.
Now, I believe I'm needed upstairs.
May I come in?
Carson?
Of course.
I'll leave you now, m'lady.
What can I do for you?
Well, I'm not sure how to start,
but before I do,
you must know that I would only
be as bold as this
if I felt it was for your benefit.
Now you're frightening me.
Your ladyship...
Do you have a moment?
What is it, Barrow?
There's something's worrying me,
m'lady and I...
I can't hold it in any more.
Why? What's happened?
It's Nanny West.
It seems she's been leaving
the children to their own devices.
What? You mean she's
neglecting them?
I wouldn't have spoken up
if it weren't for a...
..a little girl and a baby boy
being put at risk.
Carson, this is my fault.
My lady?
I'm afraid I may have
encouraged you to feel
you have the right
to address me in this way.
His lordship has made a decision
and I find it hard that his butler
should criticise him for it.
No, I never meant...
You do not seem to understand
the effect Mr Crawley's death
has had on me.
As for managing the estate,
I wouldn't know where to start.
But Mr Branson believes you could be
very helpful, my lady,
and as the agent, he should know.
He's just nervous that his lordship
will retreat to his old ways
and abandon all
Mr Matthew's reforms.
And will he?
If he did, wouldn't you approve?
Anyway, whether you approve or not,
I'm sorry you feel entitled
to overstep the mark.
My lady?
We're old friends,
and as I said, I'm sure this lapse
is as much my fault as yours.
But, I suggest we don't
mention it again.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
it's time to go down.
You're letting yourself be defeated,
my lady.
I'm sorry if it's
a "lapse" to say so,
but someone has to.
How is the luncheon
for the tenant farmers coming along?
Well, I think. Tom?
They've all accepted except
for Barnes at Wheelers Wood.
- He's sworn to his sister's wedding.
- I think we can forgive him.
I have a feeling I've double booked.
It's this Saturday, isn't it?
Don't worry.
We're not having the wives.
Edith can preside.
I can't I'm afraid.
I'm going up to London.
Mary, then.
Me?
Well, if George is owner
of half the estate now,
shouldn't you represent him?
Well, I...
I don't want to bother Mary.
They'd like to see you.
I'm sure they would but...
After all, you'll have to run it
if anything happens to Robert.
Until George is of age, or longer.
For heaven's sake! Why does everyone
keep nagging and nagging?
My husband is dead!
Can't you understand what that means?
After all he suffered in the war,
he's killed in a stupid car crash!
Matthew is dead,
50 years before his time!
Isn't that enough
for me to deal with?
Just leave me alone!
Exactly what I was afraid of.
She is living a nightmare.
We must all step back and allow her
to come through it in her own time.
Aren't I right, Mama?
No. We can't discuss it now.
This mousse is delicious, Carson,
is it the work of Mrs Patmore?
I suppose she hasn't bought it in?
I don't think so, your ladyship, no.
Then you must be sure
to send her our compliments.
What's the matter, lad?
Are you not feeling well?
No, it's not that.
Oh, I don't know, Dad. It's just...
It's just lately I...
I can't seem to see
where I'm going, I'm...
You've had a shock, and no wonder.
You should have been working for
Mr Matthew until you were old,
maybe been butler at the Abbey
before you were done.
Now all that's gone,
and your wages with it.
He were a nice chap, Dad.
You know, whatever
the difference between us,
he were always polite, always kind.
I'm glad to hear it.
But, it's raised my standards,
do you see?
I mean, who is this old... bat
her ladyship wants me
to meet on Friday?
Now, listen.
In your game, if you want the best,
you've got to BE the best.
And work at it!
Get yourself back into service,
in a good post...
..and you'll soon find your way
to where you'd like to be.
I'm leaving.
I didn't want to run off
without saying good night.
I suppose you think I behaved
very badly down there.
My dear, I'm not really
very interested
in whether you behaved badly or well.
No?
No.
I am not your governess.
I'm your grandmother.
And the difference is?
The difference is...
I love you.
Of course you do.
I'm sorry.
Mary, you've gone through
a hideous time.
But now you must remember your son.
He needs you... very much.
I know.
The truth is, I don't think
I'm going to be a very good mother.
Why not?
Because somehow,
with Matthew's death,
all the softness that he found in me
seems to have dried up
and drained away.
Maybe it was only ever there
in his imagination.
Now, my dear...
..there's more than
one type of good mother.
The fact is,
you have a straightforward choice
before you.
You must choose...
..either death... or life.
And you think I should choose life?
Charlie Grigg is going
to stay with Mrs Crawley?
The authorities have released him
into her charge.
I'm collecting him on Friday.
But why has she agreed to this?
Because she is a kind woman,
and he is a man in need.
I cannot believe you are imposing
on Mrs Crawley at a time like this,
when she is almost broken by grief.
It's BECAUSE of her grief
I am imposing.
I don't understand you.
No.
You wouldn't.
You must forgive Mary.
I do forgive her.
She is broken and bruised
and it is our job
to wrap her up and keep her
safe from the world.
No, Robert.
It is our job to bring her
back to the world.
I'm afraid that is not how I see it.
Really?
Then I can only say that while I will
overlook Mary's poor judgement,
I find it hard to overlook yours.
Goodnight.
Oh, Edith, Edith,
come to luncheon on Friday.
I...
I mean it.
I need your help
to make things a success.
Why? What are we doing?
We are selling Molesley
to Lady Shackleton.
You mean as a servant?
No. As a Chinese laundryman!
Thank God you're alone.
You've got to help me.
What's the matter with you two?
I don't know, but I'd better
go with him if I want to find out.
Oh, my Lord, what have you done?
She got a bit tiddly down the pub.
She's not tiddly. She's drunk!
He kept buying them.
What were you trying to do?
Nothing.
She's just not used to it.
Come on.
What on earth?!
Ivy's not very well.
That's the understatement
of the year. Bring her inside.
Has Mrs Patmore gone to bed?
She must have, thank goodness.
What were you trying to do?
I wasn't trying to do anything.
As long as you weren't.
Here.
How are you feeling?
A bit better, thank you.
You could have done real damage.
You come along with me now.
What about Mr Bates?
Won't he be missing you?
Mr Bates must wait his turn.
Meant no harm, Ivy, honest.
You won't say anything about this,
will you?
'Course not.
Come on.
It wasn't deliberate, you know.
I know you only pretend
to like her to tease me.
Why don't you tell her
you didn't send that card?
Oh good morning, Mrs Crawley.
I didn't know you were here.
Alfred let me in.
I wanted to see Master George,
but I'm afraid... Nanny West
didn't think it a good time.
Oh, er, Mrs Crawley...
I understand you are offering shelter
to Mr Grigg.
Yes. He's arriving this afternoon.
Only I should hate to feel
you were doing this
out of consideration for me.
Mr Grigg is perfectly capable
of managing his own affairs.
Not very successfully
if he ends up in a workhouse.
I just don't want you to waste
your energy and kindness
on an unworthy recipient.
Not at such a time.
I understand.
But you see, Carson,
I'd almost forgotten I had either
energy or kindness in me.
So that's something, isn't it?
Why is she seeing her in Ripon?
I don't know.
Her ladyship won't wait for
the advertisement to come out?
She will if this one's no good,
but she wants to get on with it.
How are you, Ivy?
Not wonderful.
I suppose we were all young once.
Yes, but you stayed young.
That's the difference.
Forgive me, Miss Braithwaite,
but I have the strangest feeling
I've seen you before.
Well, yes.
I was just coming to that.
You see, I worked at Downton Abbey,
but only for a short time.
Why was that?
I was a housemaid then, m'lady,
and I was starting to feel
it was time to move on.
I see.
So, I took a course in hairdressing,
and I could always sew.
And you got a job as a lady's maid.
I did, m'lady, but it only
lasted for a few months
because the old lady
I was working for died.
I am sorry.
I know I don't sound
very experienced, m'lady,
but I'm a very hard worker and
I've practised what I've learned.
Well, I shall obviously
have to talk to Mrs Hughes
if you've worked for us before.
She gave me a wonderful reference.
When I left.
That does seem very encouraging.
Please say yes, Cousin Cora.
You definitely want the position?
Oh, I do, m'lady.
I enjoyed Downton ever so much.
It was just that the work wasn't
sufficiently demanding.
When would you be able to start?
Whenever you want me, your ladyship.
You can make arrangements
for your aunt? My aunt?
I thought that was why you couldn't
come to Downton for the interview.
I'm sorry. Of course it was.
I'm quite dizzy I've got the job.
Erm, yes,
I can make arrangements for my aunt.
Don't worry about that.
It's settled, then.
I'm perfectly capable
of serving luncheon to three ladies.
So, why are you here?
I've an idea that she wants to
introduce me to Lady Shackleton.
Are you sure this isn't your idea?
I wonder if you haven't pushed
her ladyship into it,
so you could just show off
in front of her.
Certainly not!
I think it's my job you're after!
Nothing to do with Lady Shackleton.
No!
So you say.
Well, I'm going to announce luncheon.
But I'm warning you. That's all.
My son tells me that this decision
to remove the farm subsidies
has dealt a terrible blow to landed
estates up and down the country.
That awful Mr Lloyd George.
I agree.
You know, I sometimes wonder
if he isn't really German,
just pretending to be Welsh.
It's nice to see you here, Molesley.
Molesley's always been a great
supporter of the family.
That's good to hear.
Oh, yes, Granny and I
are always saying
there's no-one more
reliable than Molesley.
No-one.
Careful, Mr Molesley!
Oh? Are you quite well, Molesley?
Yes, your ladyship.
Oh.
What are you doing
in London, Edith dear?
Oh you know, seeing people.
There's no need to shout!
I wasn't doing anything wrong.
It looked to me as if you were
about to drop it.
Well, I wasn't.
Very well.
Here, take this.
Molesley?
I'm sorry, m'lady.
I didn't realise
the plate was so hot.
Poor man. He seems quite new
to this kind of work.
Does he?
Oh, but that is, no dear no,
that is Molesley's strength.
You see he is always
ready for a challenge.
I think it was very kind of you
to allow him to have a go at it.
Yes well, we, we try to do our best.
I do find it very hard these days
to see how many men
are forced to take employment
for which they are quite unsuited.
I hope you'll soon get back to
whatever it is you're trained for.
Come in, Mr Grigg.
Mrs Hughes has told me all about you.
Thank you, Mrs Crawley.
Oh.
I was er... I was wondering
if Charlie might be here.
Charlie Carson.
No. Mr Carson's very busy.
But, I'll tell him
that you've arrived safely.
But, he does know I'm coming here?
We talked of it yesterday.
Now, I've run a bath
and dug out some clean clothes
from the missionary barrel.
They should fit you, at least until
we can find something better.
You're very kind.
Nonsense. It's the least I can do.
While I'm sorting him out, I wondered
if you'd look in at the kitchen
and tell Mrs Field he's arrived
and to put his luncheon on a tray.
I think he should stay in bed today
and then we can see where we are.
He's right. You're very kind.
No, no. We must all do what we can.
Hello.
You look... very glamorous.
I thought I'd make
a bit of an effort.
I'm glad you did.
I've ordered some wine for us.
Heavens, how spoiling.
I love the Criterion.
It feels so wild.
To be out with a man, drinking and
dining in a smart London restaurant.
Can you imagine being allowed
to do anything of the sort
five years ago, never mind ten?
The war changed everything.
Mama used to say we could
never eat anywhere public,
except an hotel we were staying in.
She might cheat and take us to
the Ritz, but that was about it.
I do love you so.
Do you?
Hmm.
I'm glad.
Is that what we're celebrating?
That, and my progress.
I've found out I can
divorce Lizzie in Germany,
if I become a German citizen.
You're willing to become
a German citizen, for me?
You'd do that?
I'd become an Eskimo
if it meant I could marry you.
But... Germany?
After four years of fighting,
you'd join the most hated race
in Europe for me?
Can I kiss you?
What, here?
In front of all these people?
I don't care.
Kiss me. Now.
Edna Braithwaite is coming back?
I would have talked it over
with you first but...
When I saw that wonderful
reference you wrote her.
Yes, but that was because...
I wrote her a good reference because
I thought she was a good worker,
but I don't see her as a lady's maid.
Couldn't you wait for the replies
to the advertisement, m'lady,
before coming to a decision?
I'm surprised at you, Mrs Hughes.
Do you want to prevent my giving a
hard-working woman a helping hand?
You know, it WAS Jimmy
sent that card to Ivy.
You don't know that.
I think I do.
But, if it were him,
then Alfie must have sent mine.
Alfred. Come with me.
Why?
Never you mind. Just come along.
Mr Molesley? Can I get you anything?
A cup of tea?
No. I don't want to be a bother.
How was the famous luncheon?
Lady Edith told me all about it.
Was that before or after?
Before.
Right. Let's just leave it at that,
shall we?
Mrs Hughes was looking for me.
I saw her go into her sitting room.
Shall I fetch her?
No need.
I'm sorry not to have mentioned it.
I sent the card to Ivy.
But... Jimmy said...
He didn't send one.
Or, if he did,
it wasn't to anyone at Downton.
Good night, Mrs Patmore.
If it weren't him,
then who did send my card?
I won't sleep now.
Oh, for heaven's sake! I sent it.
You?!
Yes.
I thought Alfred
would buy one for Ivy,
and I didn't want you to
have nothing to open if he did.
I'm sorry if I did wrong.
No, don't be sorry.
I may not have a follower,
but at least I've got a friend.
Goodnight, Mrs Patmore.
I didn't know what else to say.
I had written her a good reference.
Only because I asked you to.
And was I to tell her that,
Mr Branson, and why you asked me?
It's up to me to tell her.
I'm the one who got us
into this fix.
No.
Her ladyship has lost a daughter
and a son-in-law.
I cannot now let her think that
Lady Sybil's husband was unworthy.
It's too much.
Then what are we to do?
We can't have her here.
We must.
We'll let her come back and we'll
make sure that she behaves herself.
And if she doesn't?
We must keep a firm eye on her,
and I hope we may rely on you to see
that Edna doesn't step out of line.
Of course.
After all, she does appear to have
acquired some proper training.
I don't think that's a lie.
Maybe she's moved
into the real world.
Well, it all sounds like
a ticking bomb to me.
There, there, my precious boy,
and don't let that chauffeur's
daughter disturb you any more.
Go back to sleep,
you wicked little cross-breed.
Your ladyship...
I didn't see you there.
Obviously not.
I was just er...
I was just having a game
with Miss Sybbie.
I want you to pack tonight and
leave first thing in the morning.
But, your ladyship...
Please put Master George
back into his crib.
You are not to touch
the children again.
Oh. I thought it was
Nanny West ringing.
No, Mrs Hughes, Nanny West
is leaving in the morning.
Can you find her a bed for the night
and ask one of the maids
to sleep with the children?
But, your ladyship,
I was only joking.
I prefer not to discuss it,
except to say that your values
have no place in a civilised home!
Now, Mrs Hughes...
I'll wait here
while Nanny West packs.
You will fetch a maid
and prepare a room.
You understand, Miss West is not to
be left alone with the children.
Not for one minute.
I wonder how Edith's getting on.
She has quite a London life.
She's seeing that publisher.
Is it serious?
Well, he's not bad looking
and he's still alive,
which puts him two points ahead
of most men of our generation.
Which doesn't alter the fact
she could do a great deal better.
Do you know anything about him?
Not really.
He talked to Matthew a bit
when we were at Duneagle...
Go to bed.
You look done in.
Do you want me at the tenants'
luncheon tomorrow?
No, there's no reason for you to be.
I know you're trying to shield me...
Let me manage things in my own way.
Please. It'll be for the best.
I have ideas, you know.
Matthew and I used to talk...
My dear, I know I'm right in this.
Now, go to bed.
My lady?
I'm sorry to bother you so late,
but I think you know why I've come.
To apologise.
You have nothing to apologise for.
I pushed into your room
and I spoke impertinently.
I suppose you know my grandmother
agrees with you.
That doesn't surprise me.
So, does this mean you've decided to
return to the land of the living?
Because, if so, I'm glad.
It means that I know that I've spent
too long in the land of the dead.
We were very fond of Mr Crawley,
you know, my lady.
All of us.
I...
You cry, m'lady.
You have a good cry.
That's what's needed now.
And when you're ready...
..you can get to work.
Because you are strong enough.
You're strong enough for the task.
But am I, Carson?
That's the point.
Papa doesn't seem to think so.
Don't you owe it to Mr Crawley,
to protect his work?
To fight for the changes he made?
To steer Downton
in the right direction?
I know I can always count on you
for a draught of self-confidence
whenever I start to doubt.
And you will always find one here.
Good night, Carson.
Good night, m'lady.
Oh my gosh.
Ohh...
What in God's name...?
I must have put those
ruddy prongs in wrong.
You did something wrong.
What a day this has
turned out to be.
Why?
Nanny West has been sacked.
So, that's fun for tomorrow.
Well, I'll get the sack
if anyone sees this!
Let Daisy and Ivy clean it up
in the morning.
But Daisy mustn't find out
I don't know how to work it.
Why ever not?
Because it makes her
part of the future
and leaves me stuck in the past,
don't you see?
Oh... Fetch me an apron.
We'll do it together.
Would you, really?
Why not?
Who needs sleep?
Thank you.
I was never sure I liked her.
Nanny West?
It's not for me to have an opinion,
but I will say this...
Where did you get to last night?
I was fast asleep before you came in
and you were sleeping when I left.
I'm afraid it was very late.
But I'm glad you're here now
because I want you to know
that we owe a great debt
to Barrow, here.
It turns out Miss West is quite
unsuited to the role of Nanny.
She is leaving today.
What? Not another one.
Trust me. We'll talk later.
I must run or I'll be late.
Barrow, I meant what I said.
Thank you.
I'm glad, your ladyship.
I just had a hunch that she
wasn't quite all Sir Garnet.
I've no problem,
as long as you test them first.
I'm so sorry to miss your arrival.
That's all right, m'lady.
We've not begun to eat.
Come and sit here.
I'll manage very well at the end.
Carson can find me a chair.
No. Sit here. I'll go to the end.
This is your place.
Are you sure you have time for this?
Quite sure.
I've been looking forward to it.
Now, Mr Taylor. What's all this
I hear about your giving up sheep?
Well, m'lady, it's not
quite as simple as that.
If truth be told,
I'd rather be farming livestock...
And why is that?
There's a letter from Matthew.
Where?
Hidden in a book in the office.
Are you trying to hide
from the truth?
That you would prefer to be
in sole charge of the estate.
There's bad feeling
between Braithwaite and Anna.
M'lord?
Anna has been a little unkind.
What's so funny?
Nothing, Mr Bates.
I want "Tom"
to be your instructor.
Are we to do all this
without telling Papa?
There can be too much truth
in any relationship.
Lady Rose asked me if I'd
chaperone her to a The Dansant.
Keep her out of trouble.
Do you want to be arrested?
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.